Inventory of the Russian subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File (Boxes 1-26, 28)
  - Soviet Union
    - American engineers, 1929-1939
      - Questionnaire
        - Responses by
          - Olberg, C. R. (Box-folder 20: 33)
          - Orr, W. S. (Box-folder 20: 34)
          - Oxnam, T. H. (Box-folder 20: 35)
          - Polakov, Walter N. (Box-folder 20: 36)
          - Scrymgeour, G. K. (Box-folder 20: 37)
          - Sibley, Robert (Box-folder 20: 38)
          - Stanton, William L. (Box-folder 20: 39)
          - Starr, C. T. (Box-folder 20: 40)
          - Swanson, Arthur (Box-folder 20: 41)
          - Thomson, Joseph L. (Box-folder 20: 42)
          - Torpen, B. E. (Box-folder 20: 43)
          - Uhler, F. W. (Box-folder 20: 44)
          - Von Meding, William (Box-folder 20: 45)
          - Wilbur, Lyman D. (Box-folder 20: 46)
        - Results (Box-folder 20: 47)
      - Subject file
        - Clemmitt, Willis B., class lecture on industrial development in the Soviet Union (Box-folder 20: 48)
        - Krejci, Milo (Box-folder 20: 49)
        - Riddell, Guy C., an analysis of progress and trends in Soviet Russia (Box-folder 20: 50)
        - Status of engineering project, 1934, 1936 (Box-folder 20: 51)
      - Writings
        - "American Engineers in Russia," report (Box-folder 20: 52)
        - "An Architect Recognizes Russia," by O. Kline Fulmer, The Architectural Forum, 1933 December (Box-folder 21: 1)
        - "Engineering Observations in the U.S.S.R.," by John M. Carmody, Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering, 1932 February (Box-folder 21: 2)
        - "First-Hand Impressions of Soviet Russia," by Raymond W. Stuck, The Case Alumnus, 1932 October-December, 1933 February, April (Box-folder 21: 3)
        - "If You Must Go to Russia," by Joseph Thompson, The Mining Journal, 1931 October 30 (Box-folder 21: 4)
        - "Impressions Gained from a Trip through Russia," synopsis of an address by R. Budd at a special meeting of the American Society of Civil Engineers, San Francisco, 1931 March 16 (Box-folder 21: 5)
        - "Journeys to the Iron Mines of Russia," by L. D. Anderson, Freyn Design, 1932 October (Box-folder 21: 6)
        - "The Korsak Pai Enterprise," by Milo W. Krejci, The Case Alumnus, 1933 December (Box-folder 21: 7)
        - "Life in a Soviet Town," by George Burrell, undated (Box-folder 21: 8)
        - "Mining Asbestos in the U.S.S.R.," by Walter Rukeyser, Engineering and Mining Journal, 1933 September (Box-folder 21: 9)
        - "My Impressions of Soviet Russia," by K. H. Donaldson, The Case Alumnus, 1932 June (Box-folder 21: 10)
        - "Production Starts at Kuznetsk," by E. P. Everhard, Freyn Design, 1932 October (Box-folder 21: 11)
        - "Red Metal Mining in Red Russia," by Joseph L. Thomson (Box-folder 21: 12)
        - "Report on the Russian Situation," by Krumb, Mayer, Reynders, Richard, Mining and Metallurgy, 1931 April (Box-folder 21: 13)
        - "Russia As I Saw It," by R. W. Stuck, 1932 May-June (Box-folder 21: 14-15)
        - "Russia as a World Factor," by William S. Wasserman, 1930 December (Box-folder 21: 16)
        - "Russia Is Planning Millions of New Electric Horse-Power Units," The Oregon Sunday Journal, 1933 March 26 (Box-folder 21: 17)
        - "Russia Reviewed by an Engineer," by Frederic Harris, The American Engineer, 1932 August (Box-folder 21: 18)
        - "Russian Lights and Shadows - A Group of Twenty Related Sketches and Stories of Contemporary Soviet Russia," by A. Hoffman, 1929 (Box-folder 21: 19)
        - "The Russian Situation as Observed by an American Railroad Man," an address by Charles A. Gill, 1932 March 1 (Box-folder 21: 20)
        - "Siberian Report to Mr. Sample," by M. Bunting, 1922 June (Box-folder 21: 21)
        - "The Situation of Russian Railroads in July 1933," lecture by engineer Kuprianov, Paris, 1933 November 15 (Box-folder 21: 22)
        - "Soviet Russia and the Five Year Industrial Plan, statement by J. S. Ferguson, 1933 April 30 (Box-folder 21: 23)
        - "Soviet Standard Blast Furnace," by Gordon Fox and Owen R. Rice, Freyn Design, 1934 March (Box-folder 21: 24)
        - "Status of Industrial Management in Russia Today," by Charles E. Stuart, 1931 October 14 (Box-folder 21: 25)
        - "There Must Be Industrial Planning," by Charles E. Stuart, 1933 December (Box-folder 21: 26)
        - "Trip to Russia," from diary of W. Robert Wood with additions from diary of Homer Bassett and excerpts from letters of H. K. Dougan (Box-folder 21: 27)
        - "U.S.S.R. Favors American Engineers and Equipment," by A. Zaviniagin, Freyn Design, 1934 March (Box-folder 21: 28)
    - American Relief Administration, 1921-1923 (Box-folder 26: 10)
    - Anti-communist propaganda (Box-folder 28: 4)
    - Armed Forces
      - "Political Control of the Soviet Armed Forces," CIA research paper, 1980 July (Box-folder 14: 3)
      - Shchedrin, G. I. Vernost' Prisiage, Izdate'stvo DOSAAF SSSR, 1985 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Arms reduction. Gorbachev, Mikhail, Agreement Now on Elimination of Soviet and U.S. Intermediate-Range Missiles in Europe, Grafischer Volkerfreundschaft, Dresden, 1987 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Atrocities. Sviashchennik Georgii, Novgorod-Severskii, "Chudovishchnye bol'shevistskie zlodeianiia v Katynskom lesu, pod Smolenskom, i v gorode Vinnitse,", 1947 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Banner, Soviet, pre-August 1991, promoting "socialist competition" among the Eastern European countries and the Soviet Union (Box 27)
    - Bortnevskii, V. G., articles (photocopies) published in the Soviet press, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Church policy. McCabe, Joseph, Russia and the Roman Church, Watts & Co., London, 1941 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Civil defense. "Soviet Civil Defense," CIA research paper, 1978 July (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Collective farms. Wronski, Henri, "La Répartition des Revenus Kolkhoziens," Revue Economique (Paris), no. 3, 1957 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - "Collective Security in Europe: Soviet Note of March 31, 1954." Soviet News booklet, London (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Communism, 1959 (Box-folder 14: 12-13)
      Pamphlets, originally chapters in the book Democracy Versus Communism (1957), by Kenneth Colegrove, relating to Soviet communism.
    - Constitution
      - "Osnovnoi zakon (Konstitutsiia),", 1922 (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - "R.S.F.S.R. Konstitutsiia,", 1918 January (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Coup d'etat, 1991 August (Box-folder 15: 3-7)
      Government documents, leaflets, newspaper and serial issues, cartoons, and other printed matter relating to events during and after the coup. In Russian.
    - Coup d'etat, 1991 August (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
    - Democratization, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 16: 3-7)
      Leaflets, pamphlets, serial and newspaper issues, election materials and other documents relating to democratic reforms and to political and social conditions in the USSR. Includes 4 lapel pins. In Russian.
    - Democratization, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 17: 1-4)
      Leaflets, pamphlets, serial and newspaper issues, election materials and other documents relating to democratic reforms and to political and social conditions in the USSR. In Russian.
    - Dissidents, 1970s (Box-folder 26: 9)
    - Economic policy. Printed matter, 1986 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Education – 45th Jewish Workers School in Khar'kov. Scrapbook with text and clippings, circa 1930s (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Emigration – Jews, 1975 (Box-folder 17: 7)
      Document describing procedure required for a Jewish Soviet citizen to procure a visa to emigrate from the Soviet Union to Israel. In Russian; includes an English translation.
    - Foreign policy
      - Bromke, Adam, The Andropov Succession: East-West Relations in the 1980s, 1983 (Box-folder 17: 8)
      - International Security Council, The Brezhnev Doctrine and the Challenge of Soviet Imperialism, New York, 1985 (Box-folder 17: 9)
      - Ward, Barbara, Russian Foreign Policy, Oxford, 1940 (Box-folder 17: 10)
    - Foreign relations
      - Canada, 1987 (Box-folder 28: 1)
      - United States, 1979 (Box-folder 28: 2)
    - Government officials. Tokaev, Grigorii Aleksandrovich, Inside the Kremlin, British Institute for Political Research, London, 1949 (Box-folder 17: 11)
    - Human rights
      - General, 1956-1984 (Box-folder 17: 11A)
        Leaflets and booklets issued by the National Alliance of Russian Solidarists (NTS); report on the Congress for Civil Rights and Freedom in Russia, held at The Hague, April 25-27, 1957.
      - Isakovich, Sergei, The Truth About Human Rights, Politvydav Ukrainy, Kiev, 1985 (Box-folder 17: 12)
    - Institute for the Study of the USSR. List of publications, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 17: 13)
    - Jews. Bugayenko, Yevgeni, On the Bank of the Amur – 50th Anniversary of the Jewish Autonomous Region, Moscow, 1984 (Box-folder 17: 14)
    - Lengorsovet (Leningrad City Soviet), Department for Issuance of Food and Supply Stamps. Report, 1942 (Box-folder 17: 15)
    - Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich
      - Krzhizhanovskii, G. M., Myslitel' i revoliutsioner, Moscow, 1985 (Box-folder 21: 28)
      - L'vov, I. A. and V. N. Utkin, "Sarai" i "shalash" v Razlive, Lenizdat, 1985 (Box-folder 21: 29)
      - Sil'vin, M. A., V dni "Soiuza bor'by za osvobozhdenie rabochego klassa," Moscow, 1985 (Box-folder 21: 30)
    - Leningrad State University. Reports, minutes of meetings, 1943-1949 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Marxist-Leninist ideology
      - General. Printed matter, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 23: 2)
      - Deriugin, Iu. I., V otvete za budushchee, Moscow, 1985 (Box-folder 23: 3)
      - Gagin, V. N., Element khudozhestvennosti v massovo-politicheskoi rabote, Moscow, 1985 (Box-folder 23: 4)
      - Ganin, N. I., Opyt Oktiabria – internatsional'noe dostoianie, Moscow, 1983 (Box-folder 23: 5)
      - "International Communism – The Soviets and the World Revolutionary Process," CIA Study, 1978 April (Box-folder 23: 6)
      - Pol'tsin, Iu., Kak vospitat' liubov' k trudu, 1985 (Box-folder 23: 7)
      - Vydrin F. A., Rabotaiushchii v odnoi iz partiinykh organizatsii, Moscow, 1985 (Box-folder 23: 8)
      - Zinoviev, G., Les questions les plus pressantes du mouvement ouvrier international, L'Internationale Communiste, Petrograd, 1920 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - Mining and metallurgy
      - General (Box-folder 23: 10)
        Studies, maps, and mine records relating to the gold mining industry in the Russian far east, Transbaikalia and Outer Mongolia. In English and Russian.
      - "L'état actuel de l'industrie minière et métallurgique de la Russie méridionale," by B. N. Sokoloff, 1921 (Box-folder 26: 13)
    - Narodnyi komissariat finansov – Economic statistics and financial planning reports, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 23: 11)
    - Narodnyi komissariat po inostrannym delam
      - Bulleten' vnutrennei informatsii, 1934 October 20, 30 (Box-folder 23: 12)
      - Declaration of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the USSR on the North-Atlantic Pact, 1949 (Box-folder 23: 13)
      - "Otvet na notu, vruchennuiu torgovym agentom Veliko-Britanskogo pravitel'stva, 8-go maia 1923 goda" (Box-folder 23: 14)
    - New York World's Fair, Soviet Pavilion, 1939 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
    - Ob'edinenie gosudarstvennykh izdatel'stv (OGIZ), Molodaia gvardiia. Propaganda pamphlets and short stories, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Peace efforts
      - Kuznetsov, Iu. F., Problemy voiny i mira: izmerenie. Mezhdunarodnye otnosheniia, 1986 (Box-folder 24: 4)
      - Naychnyi sovet po issledovaniiu problem mira i razoruzheniia, Gubitel'nye posledstviia iadernoi voiny, Moscow, 1984 (Box-folder 24: 5)
      - Religion. Segizbaev, O. A., Narodnoe samosoznanie i religiia, Alma-Ata, 1984 (Box-folder 24: 6)
      - Samizdat, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 24: 7)
        Underground samizdat writings relating to political conditions, civil liberties, and non-Russian nationalism in the Soviet Union. Includes a protest of Latvian communists against Russian national domination. In Russian.
      - Science and technology. "USSR State Committee for Science and Technology," CIA reference aid, 1985 April (Box-folder 24: 8)
      - Stalin, Joseph V. Identification cards (photocopies), 1936 (Box-folder 26: 11)
      - Tourism. Pamphlets issued by Intourist, 1937 (Box-folder 24: 9)
      - Trotsky, Leon (Box-folder 25: 1)
        Letter (typescript) from L. Trotsky to Robert T. Lincoln concerning Soviet-American relations; excerpts (typewritten carbon copy) from the English translation by Charles Malamuth of the book by L. Trotsky, Stalin: An Appraisal of the Man and His Influence; a newspaper article from La vanguardia española, 1970, by Maria Serrallach concerning the alleged illegitimate daughter of L. Trotsky in Barcelona before the Spanish civil war.
      - Tsentral'nyi ispolnitel'nyi komitet, 4aia sessiia VtsIK, 1922 October 23-28 (Box-folder 25: 2)
      - U.S. Advisory Commission of Railway Experts to Russia, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 25: 3)
        Correspondence of former members of the U.S. Advisory Commission of Railway Experts to Russia relating to the Russian revolution and activities of the commission in Siberia, 1917-1923. See also the Hoover Library for microfilm reels.
      - Vserossiiskii finansovyi s'ezd, 1922 October (Box-folder 25: 4)
      - Vyshinskii, Andrei Iu., "Ustranit' ugrozu novoi mirovoi voiny, sokhranit' mir, ukrepit' mezhdunarodnuiu bezopasnost',", 1952 October 18 (Box-folder 25: 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 26: 7-8)
  - Russians in foreign countries
    - General
      Articles appearing in the émigré press, lists of authors and titles.
      - Golos Rossii (Sofia), 1936-1938 (Box-folder 25: 6)
      - Nasha Gazeta (Sofia), 1938 October-November (Box-folder 25: 7)
      - Posledniia Novosti (Paris)
        - 1936-1937 (Box-folder 25: 8)
        - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 25: 9)
      - Vozrozhdenie (Paris), 1936-1939 (Box-folder 25: 10)
    - China, 1920-1947 (Box-folder 26: 14)
      Includes U.S. intelligence report on Russian fascist activities, 1947.
    - Yugoslavia. Biskupski, Mikhail, memorandum on Russian culture, nationalism, and religion taught at the Belgrade Russian School, 1937 October 27 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Russia (1991- )
    - Candidate materials for 1993 December 12 Duma election, circa 1993 (Box-folder 28: 5-6)
    - Communist party of the Soviet Union. "Postanovlenie Konstitutsionnogo suda Rossiiskoi Federatsii, 30 noiabria 1992 goda,", 1992 November 30 (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Democratic reforms and election of Boris Yeltsin, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 26: 3)
    - Economic conditions
      - Fond "Za ekonomicheskuiu gramotnost'," Reforma bez shoka – vybor sotsial'no-priemlemykh reshenii, Moscow-San Francisco, 1992 (Box-folder 26: 4)
      - Institute of World Economy and International Relations, "Russia and Today's Challenges," report, Moscow, 1992 (Box-folder 26: 5)
    - Political events, 1992 August-September (Box-folder 26: 6)
- Subject File (second installment) (Boxes 30-32)
  - Pre-revolutionary period
    - Compulsory regulations for building of a school with grant from the Moscow guberniia zemstvo, 1895 November 28 (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - Correspondence. Shestakova L. I., 1901 October 22 (Box-folder 30: 2)
    - Estimate of taxes for 1916, Moscow guberniia, Bogorodskii uezd (Box-folder 30: 3)
    - Laws and statutes. Kiev Court Chamber, 1906 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    - Military – Russia – Armiia
      - Letter from acting chief of General Staff, Evacuation Administration, to A. D. Samarin, head of the Russian Red Cross Society for the Interior of the Empire, 1915 February 26 (Box-folder 30: 5)
      - List of magazines allowed to the sick and wounded of the lower ranks located in various kinds of hospital installations, 1915 (?) (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - Revolutionary parties. Letter from the London Council of Workers' Union to the organizing committee of the Saint Petersburg strike, Council for the Fight for Liberation of the Working Class, 1896 August (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - Russian imperial government, Nikolaevskaia railroad, bond, 1869 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Revolution and civil war
    - Correspondence. Lieutenant-General Nikolai Golovin, 1943 (Box-folder 30: 9)
    - Decrees of the Council of People's Komissars, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 30: 10)
    - Department of Health
      - Data on contagious diseases in Kharkov guberniia, Ukraine, 1896-1921 (Box-folder 30: 11)
      - Graphs illustrating annual incidence of (5) contagious diseases in European Russia, 1918-1923 (Box-folder 30: 12)
    - Documents pertaining to General Petr Vrangel', 1920 (Box-folder 30: 13)
    - Memoirs of General Andogskii (table of contents only), 1952 (Box-folder 30: 14)
    - Samples of service seals of various Soviet military and civilian authorities, used in 1920 in territories of Eastern Poland occupied by the Red Army (Box-folder 30: 15)
    - Scrapbook of publications on G. V. Plekhanov and M. A. Bakunin, 1922-1930 (Box-folder 30: 16)
    - Tsar Nicholas II interment in Saint Petersburg, 1998 July 17 (Box-folder 30: 17)
      Invitations, newspapers, guides to the city, menu of commemorative reception.
  - Soviet Union
    - Chernobyl Nuclear Accident, Chernobyl', Ukraine, 1986
      - Causes of the accident – truth and falsehood, undated (Box-folder 30: 18)
        Signed by the salvage veterans.
      - Testimonies of victims of the disaster, undated (Box-folder 30: 19)
      - Instructions for increasing secrecy regime for labor on Chernobyl Nuclear Station, 3rd Main Headquarters, Ministry of Health of the USSR, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 30: 20)
      - Appeals
        - From the Socio-Ecological Union, Moscow, 1990 February 5 (Box-folder 30: 21)
        - From Medical Doctors for Prevention of a Nuclear War to president of the USSR Mikhail Gorbachev, 1990 May 22 (Box-folder 30: 22)
    - Democracy. American Foundation for Resistance International, Democracy Bulletin, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 30: 23)
    - Economic conditions (1917-1945)
      - Agricultural statistics for 1919, Samara Gubernatorial Statistical Bureau (Box-folder 30: 24)
      - Information on the 1921 harvest in the Republic of Georgia (wheat, barley, maize) (Box-folder 30: 25)
      - State economic plan of the Ukraine for the year 1921-1922 (Box-folder 30: 26)
    - Elections, 1989-1991
      - S'ezd narodnykh deputatov (Congress of USSR People's Deputies), 1989 (Box-folder 30: 27)
      - Regional deputies of the Ukrainian Supreme Soviet, 1989 (Box-folder 30: 28)
      - Moscow city council and mayor, 1990 March 4 (Box-folder 30: 29)
      - Regional deputies of the Russian Federation
        - First round, 1990 March 4 (Box-folder 30: 30)
        - First round, 1990 March 4 (Box-folder 31: 1)
        - Second round, 1990 March 18 (Box-folder 31: 2)
      - Leningrad city council, 1990 April 19 (Box-folder 31: 3)
      - Referendum. All union referendum on the future of the USSR, 1991 March 17 (Box-folder 31: 4)
      - Presidents – Russia, 1991 June 12 (Box-folder 31: 5)
        Includes questionnaire for Leningrad residents regarding renaming city Saint Petersburg.
    - Forced labor – Economic aspects – Soviet Union
      - Decree of the Supreme Soviet and the Council of Ministers of the USSR on punishment for divulging state secrets and losing documents containing state secrets, printed copy, 1947 June 9 (Box-folder 31: 6)
      - Drawings of Georgii Kusurgashev(?) depicting everyday life in Kolyma camps, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 31: 7)
        Includes notes. Typescript.
      - Flyer describing the Mask of Grief monument dedicated to the victims of purges at Magadan, printed copy (Box-folder 31: 8)
      - Letters, memoirs, stories, testimonies of ex-prisoners of the GULAG, 1937-1995 (Box-folder 31: 9)
        Includes copies of verdict, release certificates, certificates of death, verses, etc.
      - Maps
        - Camps located on the territory of the Magadan region in the years 1930-1950, 1994 (Box-folder 31: 10)
          Paraphrased legend: This map was compiled with the help of ex-prisoners and civil servants, and declassified KGB documents, which made it possible to find out the exact location of the camps, mines, timber industry, road distances, etc. The map contains about 400 locations, previously parts of the GULAG system. The author of this map is I. Panikarov, Yagodnoe village, Magadan region.
        - Orientation chart of Kolyma camps and surrounding territories, undated (Box-folder 31: 11)
      - Publications on years of repression, Magadan, 1990-1998
        - Khudozhniki-uzniki kolymskikh lagerei, Magadan, printed copy, 1996 (Box-folder 31: 12)
        - Pamiat' Kolymy: vospominaniia, pis'ma, fotografii o godakh repressii, Magadan, printed copy, 1990 (Box-folder 31: 13)
        - Savchenko, B., Opal'nyi Orfei: sud'ba i tvorchestvo Vadima Kozina, Magadan, printed copy, 1991 (Box-folder 31: 14)
        - Vaishvillene, N. A., Sud'ba i volia ili gor'kie vospominaniia, Magadan, printed copy, 1998 (Box-folder 31: 15)
        - Zolotaia truba: zhizn' i tvorchestvo Eddi Roznera, Magadan, printed copy, 1998 (Box-folder 31: 16)
    - Foreign relations
      - China, 1917-1945. Sinkiang Province, 1928-1931(?) (Box-folder 31: 17)
        Holograph, in Russian.
      - Czechoslovakia, 1953-1975. Prospectus of publication on events in Prague [1968], 1997 (Box-folder 31: 18)
      - Gorbachev, Mikhail, "Entering the Twenty-First Century," speech delivered at World Peace Conference, Seoul, Korea, 1994 (Box-folder 31: 19)
      - State of the World Forum, San Francisco, 1995 September 27 - October 1 (Box-folder 31: 20)
        Includes Mikhail Gorbachev's book The Search for a New Beginning: Developing a New Civilization, 1995.
    - History – 1953-1985. Verdict concerning Lavrentii P. Beriia, 1953 December 23 (Box-folder 31: 21)
      Signed by Prosecutor General Rudenko, and Generals Moskalenko and Bagitskii.
    - Samizdat (Box-folder 31: 22)
      Underground Samizdat writings relating to political conditions, civil liberties, and non-Russian nationalism in the Soviet Union. Includes Samizdat publication on a conference concerning 30 years of independent press, 1950-1980. Printed copy. In Russian.
    - Secret service – Russia. Veterans of Russian foreign intelligence service, Moscow, printed copy, 1995 (Box-folder 31: 23)
  - Russians in foreign countries, Stanichnyi vestnik, Obshche-kazach'ia stanitsa imeni Atamana Kaledina (The Messenger, All Cossack Association), Montreal, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 32: 1)
- Subject File (third installment) (Boxes 32-45)
  - Commonwealth of Independent States - Russia (Federation)
    - General
      - Russian Constituent Union, constituent conference, Moscow, 1992 November 14-15 (Box-folder 32: 2)
        Includes draft of the Constitution of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics of Europe and Asia. Printed copy.
      - Attempted coup [coup d'etat], 1991 August (Box-folder 32: 3)
        Government documents, broadcasts, leaflets, newspaper, serial issues, and printed matter relating to the events during and after the coup. In Russian.
      - Referendum on Yeltsin's policies "Da, da, net, da,", 1993 April 25 (Box-folder 32: 4)
      - October crisis, 1993 (Box-folder 32: 5)
        Government documents, appeals, open letters, leaflets, newspapers, and other printed matter relating to the October events in Moscow.
    - Elections, 1992-2001
      General note
      See also Poster Collection
      Appeals, leaflets, open letters, proclamations, calendars, pamphlets, serial and newspaper issues, election material, and posters, relating to democratic reforms, political parties, and social conditions in Russia.
      - General (Box-folder 32: 6)
      - Parliamentary, 1993-1999
        - 1993 December 12 (Box-folder 32: 7)
        - 1995 December 17
          - General (Box-folder 32: 8)
          - General (Box-folder 33: 1-4)